Stefanos Stefanou

Software Engineer

♦ +44(0)7706066959
★ TODO
★ stefannstefanou@gmail.com
♦ http://stefanos.isactually.cool

Personal Profile

I am a Software engineer based in Hemsworth, UK. I am enthusiastic about everything I do, I behave well under pressure, and I am passionate about excellence. I can acquire and apply knowledge fast, and I adapt quickly to any situation. I have over three years of commercial functional scala experience in various firms, working in data-intense event-sourced and distributed systems. My hobbies include interest in Mathematics, Physics and Functional programming.

Core Skills

• Typelevel Scala

• Akka

• Neo4J

• Fs2

• MongoDB, Elastic, Solr

Docker

Kafka

• PostgresSQL

• AWS

Career Summary

6/2021 - present Software Engineer GB Group Plc

Role outline

As a software engineer at GBG, i am working on the 'Investigate' Product, providing identity identification, location inteligence and fraud prevention on B2B clients around the world

5/2020 - 6/2021 Software Engineer J Sainsburys PLC - Sainsburys Tech

Role outline

Supporting the unified pricing and promotions system of the Sainsburys Group, a event-sourced data-intensive distributed system, Extensive use of Kafka, Akka, Fs2 as well as various Typelevel libraries

2/2019 - 5/2020 Ascosiate Software Engineer TALOS Software LTD

Role outline

As an ascosiate software engineer at TALOS, i worked extensively on the companys biggest product yet, 'Simply-book', mainly around the backend system. Use of Scala play, Typelevel Scala, Akka as well as Cypress/Gatling for testing purposes

10/2018 - 2/2019 Research Assistant University of Reading

Role outline

Developing customized filesystem solutions for High- performance computers using FUSE(ESIWACE Project), extensive use of C, Python, and non relational databases such as MongoDB and ElasticSearch

2018 AIIA Low Latency Video Streaming Challenge 2018 (1rst)
Aristotle University of Thessaloniki, Greece

Role outline

Developing a customized solution for ICARUS LAB experimental surveillance drones, transfering real-time video and telemetry data with minimal latency, the end-result, alanStreamer was written using C++, C, QT, gstream

2016 International Open Bidding Competition 2016 (Team 2nd)

Organiser: Université Sorbonne Paris Nord, France

Role outline

Functional prototype of a web information system while meeting all requirements set by a project committee, Extensive use of PHP, HTML/CSS, Node.js and MySQL

2015 28th National Information Technology Competition (30th place, Finals)

Organiser: National Technical University of Athens

Role outline

Greece's national algorithmic student competition, finishing at 30th place (final stage), nation-wide, Various problems focused on Dynamic Programming, Minimum Spanning Trees and various number-theory related algorithms

Interesting Projects

2016	\mathbf{DFS} (Dummy File System, C and Linux Kernel 4.0.X)
2016	SScheduler (Stefano's Scheduler, simple linux scheduler implementation for kernel 4.X)
2018	'Java for the few'(Book) (Worked on 3 chapters, Book is used on 2 universities (Uniwa, AUEB))

Education

2018-2022 Bsc Computer Science University of Reading

Role outline

- First Class Degree
- Dissertation: An AI-assisted decision making system for thyroid nodule classification